# YASMEEN COLE

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

(423)305-8021 | YASMEENCOLE1@GMAIL.COM | LINKEDIN | GITHUB

# **ABOUT ME**

I have a life long interest in learning about technology and the many ways it has helped to improve and shape our environment. As a child I participated in summer programs at the Challenger Center for Space Science Education, where I participated in simulated space missions, and learned about space based technologies. These experiences sparked a life long interest in space sciences, engineering and technology.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- React
- Python
- Django
- SQL
- CSS
- HTML

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Nashville Software School

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT 2021** 

## **University of Tennessee - Knoxville**

FOOD SCIENCES & TECHNOLOGY | 2010-2014

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Developer**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- Intensive hands-on six month full-stack software development apprenticeship focusing on:
  - Javascript, React, Python and Django,
    HTML, CSS and server-side fundamentals.
  - Database planning using entity relationship diagrams (ERD) to define relationships and maintain a flat data structure.

#### **Senior Business Assistant**

WILLIS TOWERS WATSON | AUGUST 2017 - JANUARY 2021

- Reviewing contracts and interpreting data to verify requested requirements against policy guidelines, working directly with client managers and insured parties to evaluate needs and provide/create proper certifications such as certificates of insurance, auto identification cards, and endorsements.
- Operating in-house insurance account management software, using spreadsheet and word processing software to obtain insurance data and issue certificates.

#### **Appeals Specialist**

BLUE CROSS BLUE SHIELD | JUNE 2016 - JULY 2017

- Retrieving and preparing documentation for: batching, suspends claims in appropriate claim and internal system, builds case files, copies, faxes, and logs data.
- Maintaining databases and updating the system for tracking purposes to ensure timeliness and quality standards are met.
- Performing administrative workflow of reconsideration requests received within timeliness and quality standards.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Front End Capstone

- My Food Journal, a single page application created to help users with gastrointestinal issues document daily their foods intake and eliminate problem foods from their diet.
- The technologies used include:
  - React JS, React Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, and JSON server

#### **Nutshell Talisman of Havocing**

- A single page application created for people to be able to organize their: daily tasks, events, news articles, friends, and chat messages.
- The technologies used include:
  - Javascript, React, CSS, and HTML

### **Accidental Engines**

- A single page application that allows users to build a travel itinerary based off of: national parks, eateries and attractions throughout the United States.
- The technologies used include:
  - o Javascript, CSS, HTML and API's

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Teacher Assistant**

METROPOLITAN NASHVILLE PUBLIC SCHOOLS | DECEMBER 2015 - JUNE 2016

- Partner with lead teacher to plan and implement lessons following school's curriculum, goals, objectives and philosophies
- Provided one-on-one and group-based learning support to maintain student progress and development.

#### **Sales Representative**

FEDEX | FEBRUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

- Make and receive outbound/inbound calls to/from clients to sell and endorse services that are best suited to enhance client's productions.
- Resolve and respond to customers inquires, needs, and requirements. Set up new business accounts for clients and document inbound/outbound call history.

# Microbiology Research Assistant

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE | JANUARY 2013 - AUGUST 2014

- Experimented with various antimicrobials to determine the kill point and the effects the antimicrobials have on Enterobacter aero genes and Staphylococcus aureus.
- Retrieving and preparing documentation for: organizing experiments to isolate and grow cultures of microorganisms under controlled conditions, prepare agar plates, dilation tubes, etc.
- Plan, modified and executed research techniques, procedures and tests.
- Prepared materials for reports, presentations and submissions to peerreviewed journal publications.